KALYANI SINGH

Specialist-Software Engineer

+91-8788171758



kalyani101090@gmail.com



Pune,India



SUMMARY

Passionate Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience in developing web applications and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. Able to work independently of remote locations or in office environments as needed by the company.

EDUCATION

VIT University, Vellore, TN

M.Tech(Computer Science and Engineering) 2014-2016

Uttaranchal Institute Of Technology, Dehradun •

B.Tech(Computer Science and Engineering) 2009-2013

SKILLS

- Strong organizational and timemanagement skills
- Ability to work independently and as part of a team
- Detail-oriented and able to handle multiple tasks simultaneously
- Experience in technical write up for RFP's

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Java,J2EE
- Spring, Hibernate, Microservices
- Liferay DXP
- MySQL
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery
- GIT, SonarCube, Jenkins, Eclipse
- Junit

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Specialist-Software Engineer

LTIMindtree | 2022 - Present

- Responsible for understanding the client's requirements, requirement analysis and proposing a feasible solution.
- Responsible for effort estimation of the requirement and creating task for the user stories.
- Developed utilities that can be used as assets to other projects. Responsible for preparing Functional Design Document.
- Responsible for infrastructure setup and deployment in different development environments (SIT, UAT, Pre-Prod, PROD).
- Create & maintain project documentation including issue trackers, delivery trackers & resource utilization. Responsible for code reviews, code merge and deployment to different development environments.
- Lead a team of 7 members & helped the team in getting trained on Liferay DXP.
- Worked on technical write up documents for RFPs (Request for Proposals).
- Responsible for developing the assigned task and unit testing of assigned modules

Senior Software Engineer

Infosys | 2021-2022

- Responsible for requirement analysis, interacting with clientbased/onsite developers to validate the understanding and actively involved as a team member for the development of module.
- Responsible for implementing OOB features provided by Liferay like Forms, Pages and Web Content, Workflows, Dynamic Data List, custom portlet, etc.
- Responsible for Implementing web services and consuming existing web services and implementing Junit for each module.
- Helping team members for DevOps activities

REFERENCES

Reference 1:

Name: Vipul R Khatavkar Relation: Colleague

Email: Vipul.r.khatavkar@accenture.com

Mobile: +91 97300 36648

Reference 2:

Name: Beena J Relation: Colleague

Email: Beena.J@Intinfotech.com

Mobile: +91 98412 75911

Senior Software Engineer

Accenture | 2018 - 2020

- Responsible for requirement analysis, solution design and as a team member for the development of assigned user stories.
- Responsible for implementing OOB features provided by Liferay like Forms, Pages, and Web Content. Responsible for code review activities, static code analysis and branching strategies.
- Responsible for training and conducting workshops for new onboards in Liferay technology.
- Actively involved in the post deployment application monitoring and release management.

Software Engineer

Wipro Technologies | 2016 - 2018

- Responsible for structuring and performing Data Lineage Analysis for Risk and Finance Reports across the risk and finance processes and infrastructure.
- Responsible for defining and refining the Data lineage approach and obtain buy in from relevant internal/external stakeholders (auditors, regulators).
- Responsible for executing and managing the progress of the work against quality standards and targets.
- Responsible for performing unit testing using JUnit and component testing for new custom rules.